NETWORK SECURITY ENGINEER IT CONSULTANT

Profile

Proactive Systems and Network Security Engineer with experience in databases upgrade and migration, development and maintenance of complex critical systems. Proficient at managing McAfee network security manager for Intrusion Prevention Systems and Intrusion Detective Systems. Expert on designing, implementing, customizing, upgrading, and migrating systems in large server farm environments. Perform all duties in accordance with corporate guidelines, policies, procedures, regulations, and standards. Support Local Area Network (LAN) and Wide Area Network (WAN). Compliance with HIPAA and HITECH. Highlights Project Management Network Administration Wireless Cisco Systems (WCS) Database Servers Systems Administration NetIQ & Spectrum Console McAfee ePO Servers Information Security System Diagnose & Maintenance Installation & Configuration Research & Development Strategic Planning & Troubleshooting Patch Management Virtualization Infrastructure Excellent Problem Solving Skills

Professional Experience

Network Security Engineer IT Consultant 06/2014 to Current New York City Health & Hospitals Corporation City, STATE

• RennerBrown via CompuCom System Perform administration tasks in McAfee ePO console and also perform reports and queries creation Handle and eliminate threats that are identify on the network using McAfee IPS and IDS sensors Patch and update the IPS and IDS sensors with updated signatures and Common Vulnerability Exposure to prevent threats Manage and monitor threats using McAfee Network Security Manager and HP ArcSight console Maintain McAfee ePO encryption with local and external drives for electronic protected health information (ePHI) Follow incident response guidelines such as detection, analysis, containment, eradicate, and recovery to remove threats Administer Windows server 2003/2008/2012 Scan all production systems using McAfee Vulnerability Manager to find systems that are vulnerable to threats Be part of the Incident Response Team to handle network attacks including malicious codes, unauthorized access, virus events Review and approve risk acceptance to mitigate risk in the environment Create and assign incident and change request tickets using BMC Remedy system Utilize excellent listening skills and strong written and spoken communication skills to enhance collaboration Documents every incident and system changes in the environments Investigate and research exploit attempt occurs in the DMZ network using various security tools.

Infrastructure Engineer IT Consultant 07/2010 to 08/2014 CompuCom System Kings County Hospital Center City, STATE

• Provided basic Microsoft SQL database support by implementing SQL server, upgrading, and migrating databases Administered Microsoft SCCM 2007/2012 to create and deploy packages to managed systems and created Task Sequence Implemented and administered Windows Server 2003/2008/2012 including Active Directory, Group Policies, and WSUS Managed and maintained VMware ESXi host servers to provide virtual hardware platforms while keeping hardware cost and energy consumption down Migrated obsolete hardware platforms to VMs via VMware vCenter with vMotion support Maintained and troubleshoot wireless network for hospital mobile carts including medication carts and flo-carts Performed Active Directory user accounts, groups, and QuadraMed QCPR provider accounts creation Resolved escalated issues related to applications and servers and interacted with their vendors as soon as possible Created frontend RPC proxy servers and back-end mail servers Implemented disaster recovery plan by performing backup and restoration using VERITAS Backup Exec and TSM client Assigned as a Windows 7 lead engineer to supervise 15 technicians to deploy over 4000 Windows 7 workstations in 6 months Monitored and generated alerts for critical servers, routers, and switches with Spectrum OneClick and NetIQ.

Desktop Support Analyst IT Consultant 07/2008 to 07/2010 Core Technology Solutions CompuCom System Kings County Hospital Center City , STATE

Installed and configured printers and scanners Deployed and managed wyse zero clients and thin clients Administered Leostream
Connection Broker to manage VMs Managed VMware vCenter server to restart and shutdown VMs Configured barcode scanners to be
used in QuadraMed QCPR system Worked independently to identify and troubleshoot VMs issues, also collaborated with VDI teams to
resolve issues Utilized excellent listening skills and strong written and spoken communication skills to enhance collaboration Maintained Help
Desk specific applications and assisted in refining procedures Installed and deployed workstations to the medical staffs Performed Windows
7 ghost image to be deployed Created and assigned incident tickets using BMC Remedy system.

Education

CompTIA A+ IT Technician CCENT - Cisco Certified MCSA - Windows Server 2003 CompTIA Network+ CCNA - Cisco Certified MCSE - Windows Server 2003 CompTIA Security+ CCNA - Security MCSA - Windows Server 2008 CCA - Citrix Certified CCNP - Cisco Certified MCTS - Windows Server 2008 VCP4 - VMWare Certified VCP5 - VMware Certified Bachelor of Science : Computer Science University of Cape Coast Ghana Computer Science

A+, Active Directory, backup, basic, CCNA, CCNP, Cisco Certified, Citrix, CCA, communication skills, hardware, encryption, client, clients, databases, database, disaster recovery, engineer, ghost, Help Desk, HP, IDS, image, listening, McAfee, access, MCSE, mail, Windows 7, Windows, Network Security, Network, Policies, printers, proxy, research, routers, scanners, servers, Microsoft SQL, SQL server, switches, Technician, troubleshoot, TSM, upgrading, VERITAS Backup, VMs, written